Hayden Barnett

Frontend Engineer

haydenbarnett.com hello@haydenbarnett.com 0488199725

About

Senior frontend engineer focused on high quality UI/UX with over 10 years of experience building accessible and performant interfaces and design systems in various industries.

Living in Sydney, Australia.

Skills

HTML CSS SCSS Tailwind JavaScri

JavaScript TypeScript

React Next Vue

Nuxt

Figma
Adobe Photoshop
Adobe Illustrator
Adobe After Effects

Education

Bachelor of Information Technology

2009 - 2011 Graduated with Distinction

Charles Sturt University

Major

Software Design & Development

Minor

Animation & Visual Effects

Experience

Senior Frontend Engineer • Corellium

2021 - Present (1 year)

Worked with the newly formed frontend team on a range of new projects while also evolving and maintaining the existing core app.

- New design system, onboarding flow app, marketing website & cloud administration platform. All built on React, Next.js, TypeScript.
- Maintaining the existing Corellium app working with product, middleware and device modelling teams.
 - Implemented device interaction features, administration features, enterprise whitelabelling and more, as well as performing a lot of bug fixing.
 - o Supported launch of multiple Android, iPhone, IoT devices.
 - Implemented design token systems, improved accessibility, evolved UI design.
 - Conversion to functional components, TypeScript, CSS modules and then Tailwind.
- Planned & implemented GA, GTM, Segment across all external user facing apps.

Senior UX Engineer • Koala

2020 - 2021 (1 year)

Joined at an exciting time, just before the company underwent a rebrand, a launch into a new market and a complete digital transformation.

- Maintained the legacy eCommerce websites (Vue, Nuxt, Shopify)
- o Built the new design system following the rebrand
- Helped rebuild the eCommerce platform on a new tech stack (Nx, React, TypeScript, Commerce Tools, Contentful)
- Relaunched the rebranded Koala platform in Australia, Japan, and Korea simultaneously

Creative Director • Surge

2018 – 2021 – Part Time (3 years)

Co-founded a growth marketing agency and was responsible for managing the creative output, including development, design, copywriting, and video production. Our clients included CSIRO/Data61, Waddle, TutorTime, Dysrupt Labs, and Jellypepper.

Frontend Developer • Tyro Payments

2016 - 2020 (4.5 years)

Worked as the owner of the Tyro website, responsible for frontend development, design, and content, including the launch of digital marketing campaigns, projects, partnerships, and initiatives.

- Improved the functionality, design, and performance of tyro.com, focusing on optimization for conversion, accessibility, usability, and security.
- o Supported the Tyro rebrand with the new website launch.

- o Helped with the work leading up to the company's ASX listing.
- Designed, built, and iterated on the digital application solution for new customers, supporting all lead generation and the self-serve application process.
- Maintained analytics integration across multiple platforms, including GA, VWO, Mixpanel, Flashtalking, Adroll, Quantcast, Taboola, Ruler, Pardot, and Salesforce.
- Contributed to CRO efforts, supporting the ideation and execution of growth-related experiments. Built a suite of functional web tools for SMEs, such as a fee analyser, loan calculator, and POS recommendation tool.
- o Managed two creative agencies to deliver increased work output.
- Worked on the initial launch of the Tyro Merchant Portal, which enables customers to view real-time payment reports, reconcile their accounts, and order accessories.

Frontend Developer • Redpin Design

2014 - 2016 (2 years)

Worked on a range of projects involving web development, design, branding, EDM campaigns & competitions. Clients include CASF, Sekisui, Tismor, CRC, OCP, Snack Brands, Green's, Auspath and Pace Farm.

Partner • Gunmetal Studio

2013 – 2014 (1.5 years)

Co-founded a web design and development studio, providing services to a diverse range of clients from startups to corporate and entertainment companies. Notable clients include National Geographic Channel, FX, Vimbra, Trekalo, Ryzer, and Wild Animal Encounters.

Frontend Developer & Designer • Nexba Beverages

2013 (2 months)

Design and web development as an intern, working on the Nexba eCommerce website.

Motion Designer • BSA Limited

2012 (2 months)

Contract work on a range of projects involving motion graphics, visual effects, graphic design, and web development.

Freelance

2008 - Present - Part Time (over 10 years)

Throughout my career, I have been involved in freelance work building websites and developing branding for companies and startups. In recent years, most of this work has been carried out through my agency, Surge. Some of my notable clients include Clipchamp, Tank Stream Ventures, Flaunter, Flirtey, and Zibbet.